Guide to the Betsy Beinecke Shirley Collection of American Children's Literature
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- American History and Educational Materials, 1640-1966; Series II; 4; (9 boxes)
  - Smith, John Jay
    - Letter to J. Lorimer Graham Jr., regarding proposed book on poets, 1860 Oct 30 (Box 25, Folder 452)
  - Steichen, Edward
    - Statement regarding The Family of Man exhibition, undated (Box 25, Folder 453)
  - Steinberg, Susan
    - Workbook with sewing samples, circa 1920 (Box 25, Folder 454)
  - Sumner, Esther Puffer
    - Receipt for goods received from her father Matthias Puffer at her marriage to William Sumner, circa 1697 (Box 26, Folder 455)
  - Taylor, John
    - Letter to Henry Sherburne, regarding the health and education of children of the family; reply drafted on integral address leaf, 1749 Sep 28 (Box 26, Folder 456)
  - Thomas, Isaiah
    - Letter to unidentified publisher, regarding exchange of printed works, 1791 Oct 7 (Box 26, Folder 457)
  - Thompson family
    - Rewards of merit (6), biographical notes (3), and quotation; holograph and printed ephemera, 1821-1826, undated (Box 26, Folder 458)
  - Toadlena (N.M.) Boarding School
    - Manuscript book of essays and drawings by students describing Navajo life; mixed media, with plywood covers, circa 1930 (Box 26, Folder 459-460)
  - Trotter, Mary
    - Workbooks for penmanship (4), 1810-1813 (Box 26, Folder 461-464)
  - Trotter, Rebecca
    - Autograph album, 1824-1826 (Box 26, Folder 465)
  - Vergoose, Isaac
    - Indenture for division of estate, signed by Vergoose's four children, Peter, Isaac, Anna, and Elizabeth, and Elizabeth's husband, the printer Thomas Fleet, 1734 Feb 21
  - Victoria, Queen of Great Britain
    - Letter to her grandson Maurice; holograph, 1899 Apr 14 (Box 26, Folder 466)
  - Vivion, John
    - Last will and testament, Fayette County, Virginia, regarding disposition of his young slaves, 1805 (Box 26, Folder 467)
  - Wadsworth, Benjamin
    - Sermons, dating from August 27, 1710, to February 11, 1711; holograph, bound volume, 1710-1711 (Box 26, Folder 468)
  - Ware, Samuel Wheaton
    - Workbook, for penmanship; holograph, 1823 (Box 26, Folder 469)
  - Washington, George
    - Letter to George Steptoe Washington, regarding advice for the conduct of his life, 1789 Mar 23 (Box 27, Folder 470)
  - Wentworth, Jaazaniah
    - Poem, "Education"; holograph, 1821 Mar 15
    - Workbook for arithmetic; holograph, 1817 (Box 27, Folder 471)
  - White, William Allen
    - Letter to Fred Dudley, regarding papers his class had written about White's work; typed letter signed, 1935 Jun 12 (Box 27, Folder 472)
  - Whiting, Mary Elizabeth Flint
    - Diary of journey to Assam on board the ship Washington Allston, with Baptist missionaries; holograph, 1850 (Box 27, Folder 473)
  - Willard, John
    - Letter to Jedediah and Dorothy Foster, regarding the death of their daughter, 1779 Aug 10 (Box 27, Folder 474)
  - Wingate, Frank S.
    - Autograph, undated (Box 27, Folder 475)
  - Winslow, Hannah
    - Calligraphy design, "Twenty Four Letter" [sic]; holograph, undated (Box 27, Folder 476)
  - Yantic School District (Norwich, Conn.)
    - Inhabitants complaint to the committee of the first School Society in the towns of Norwich, Bozrah, and Franklin; holograph, 1821 Mar 27 (Box 27, Folder 477)
  - Unidentified artists and authors
    - Album of flowers from the Holy Land; pages hold pressed dried flowers and plants arranged into various designs, with inlaid wood covers, 1877 (Box 27, Folder 478)
    - Album of gem-format portrait photographs; tintypes, undated (Box 27, Folder 479)
    - Album, "Pictures from Life," created for Caroline Frothingham Neal; collages with narrative inscribed in ink, 1865
    - Album, carte-de-visite format, with photographs of unidentified children and adults, undated (Box 28, Folder 480-481)
    - Composition with valentine and paper inscribed "Nancy Hawk"; watercolor and collage on paper, framed, 1838, undated
    - "Embroidery patterns," printed page showing floral patterns and borders; accompanied by fragments of green and blue embroidery thread and label for "Asiatic Dyes/Filo Selle", undated (Box 29, Folder 482)
      Removed from Shirley 3049
    - Letter from "Santa Claus"; holograph, undated (Box 29, Folder 483)
    - List of Chinook words; holograph, undated (Box 29, Folder 484)
    - Manuscript booklet, "Peary's Trip to the Land of the Midnight Sun;" pencil, crayon, and collage, undated (Box 29, Folder 485)
    - Notebook, "Indian canticles for all days of the week," in Clallam language; holograph, circa 1900 (Box 29, Folder 486)
    - Photograph, portrait of a baby; albumen print, undated (Box 29, Folder 487)
      Removed from Folio Shirley 92
    - Photographs, portraits of two children; ambrotype and albumen carte-de-visite print, undated (Box 29, Folder 488)
    - Photographic negatives (2) of covers of The Boy's Home Weekly, vol. 1, nos. 1 and 8; glass and film, undated (Box 29, Folder 489)
    - Quotations; holograph, 1825-1826 (Box 29, Folder 490)
    - Rebus letters (2), 1873, 1874 (Box 29, Folder 491)
    - Rewards of merit; holograph, 1825-1834, undated (Box 29, Folder 492)
    - Sampler; embroidery on linen, undated (Box 29, Folder 493)
    - School absence notes, Newark, New Jersey; holograph, 1888-1906 (Box 29, Folder 494-495)
    - Sermons; holograph, in bound volume, circa 1820 (Box 30, Folder 496)
    - Sketchbook, with studies of heads, faces, and people; pencil and wash on paper, circa 1850 (Box 30, Folder 497)
    - Sketches, miscellaneous, including story featuring a flock of sheep, undated (Box 30, Folder 498)
- Other Papers, 1836-1968; Series III; 0.84; (3 boxes)
  Series III is arranged in three subseries: J. Austin Sperry Papers, Leon M. Tyrrell Papers, and Edward Stratemeyer Papers.
  The series holds discrete archival collections acquired by Betsy Beinecke Shirley two of which, in content and scope, fall outside the material held in Series I and II. The first subseries, J. Austin Sperry Papers, does have a slight relationship to children's literature through the few poems and stories written by Sperry (1823-1896), a Southern newspaperman, while a youth in Virginia. Sperry attended medical school in Baltimore, after which he turned to a career in journalism; he owned and published newspapers in Knoxville, Tennessee, Bristol, Virginia, and Augusta, Georgia, during his lifetime. He also published one novel, had at least one of his plays produced on the New York stage, and his short stories appeared in various serials starting in the 1840s. The papers here consist mostly of literary manuscripts, primarily drafts and unfinished works. Sperry was a distant relative of the Beinecke family through Betsy Shirley's mother Katherine Sperry Beinecke.
  The second subseries, Leon M. Tyrrell Papers, holds neither literary nor children's material, but rather letters and documents relating to the Alaskan gold rush of 1898. It contains six letters sent by Tyrrell (born 1875) to his father Vernon and other family members in Bradford County, Pennsylvania, in 1898 and 1899, from Wrangell and other locations in Alaska. In his letters Tyrrell describes his activities (sailing, fishing, hunting, hiking, and panning for gold), surroundings (landscapes, including glaciers), companions (fellow prospectors, Indians, birds, and wild animals), and thoughts on a variety of topics. Also included are eight legal documents regarding placer mine claims that Tyrrell filed on behalf of family and friends in Pennsylvania.
  The third subseries, Edward Stratemeyer Papers, does concern children's literature, specifically the career of one of its most prolific authors and publishers. A native of Elizabeth, New Jersey, Stratemeyer (1862-1930) wrote several series of popular novels for boys and girls, including the Hardy Boys and Rover Boys adventures, and founded the Stratemeyer Syndicate of writers who turned out hundreds of titles under pseudonyms. The small collection of papers here concerns Stratemeyer's own life and career, with some later documents regarding his daughter, Harriet Stratemeyer Adams, who wrote for the syndicate. It contains biographical material, correspondence, contracts and other legal documents, story outlines, an opera libretto, receipts, clippings, and photographs which pre-date and supplement the Beinecke Library's Stratemeyer Syndicate Records (GEN MSS 107). Drawings for Stratemeyer Syndicate publications, acquired separately, appear in Series I.
  - J. Austin Sperry papers
    - Correspondence, 1841-1854 (Box 31, Folder 499)
    - Lectures/speeches, undated (Box 31, Folder 500)
    - Medical notes, undated (Box 31, Folder 501)
    - Novel: "Little Finn, or, The History of a Successful Financier"; fair copy, circa 1868 (Box 31, Folder 502-503)
    - Novel: "Little Finn, or, The History of a Successful Financier"; draft pages, undated (Box 31, Folder 504-505)
    - Plays, 1845, undated (Box 31, Folder 506-509)
    - Poems, 1836, 1842, undated (Box 31, Folder 510)
    - Stories, undated (Box 32, Folder 511-515)
    - Story fragments, undated (Box 32, Folder 516-517)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, 1846, undated (Box 32, Folder 518)
  - Leon M. Tyrrell papers, 1898-1899 (Box 32, Folder 519-520)
  - Edward Stratemeyer Papers
    - Biographical material and portrait photograph, 1879-1917, undated (Box 33, Folder 521)
    - Correspondence and copyrights, 1888-1907 (Box 33, Folder 522-523)
    - Libretto: "The Perfume Prince. Comic Novelty Opera in Three Acts.", 1888 (Box 33, Folder 524)
    - Outlines, synopses, proposals, undated (Box 33, Folder 525)
    - Contracts, 1914-1919, 1948 (Box 33, Folder 526)
    - Will and estate papers, 1930-1936 (Box 33, Folder 527)
    - Receipts, 1905-1914 (Box 33, Folder 528)
    - Miscellaneous clippings and ephemera, 1902-1968 (Box 33, Folder 529)
- OVERSIZE
  - André, R. (Richard): drawings (15) for By Land & Water; ink and watercolor on paper, dummy, with notes regarding changes (in Series I), circa 1888 (Box 34, Folder 530)
  - André, R. (Richard): drawings (4): "Santa Claus in the Stable," "Santa Claus in his Library," "Santa Claus in his Workshop," and "Well-Earned Repose"; watercolor on paper mounted on linen (in Series I), circa 1888 (Box 34, Folder 531)
  - Angelo, Valenti: drawings (3) for The Tale of a Donkey; pencil on paper (in Series I), circa 1965 (Box 34, Folder 532)
  - Angelo, Valenti: drawing for dust jacket of The Tale of a Donkey; gouache, ink and colored pencil on bristol board (in Series I), circa 1965 (Box 34, Folder 533)
  - Bobbett, Walter: drawing, "The little old man of Dyre"; ink on bristol board (in Series I), 1884 (Box 34, Folder 534)
  - Bransom, Paul: drawings (4) for The Call of the Wild, by Jack London; pencil, watercolor, and charcoal on paper (in Series I), circa 1912 (Box 34, Folder 535)
  - Bruton, W. (William): drawing, for poster for pantomime toy books (in Series I), circa 1880 (Box 34, Folder 536)
  - Bruton, W. (William): sketches for "Johnnie Headstrong's Trip to Central Park"; pencil on paper (in Series I), circa 1882 (Box 34, Folder 537)
  - Burgess, Gelett: drawings (40), sketches and final drawings for The Burgess Nonsense Book; pencil and ink on paper, bristol board, and illustration board (in Series I), 1898-1904 (Box 35, Folder 538-544)
  - Cady, Harrison: drawings (2) for "The Happychaps," by Carolyn Wells; ink and pencil on bristol board (in Series I), circa 1908 (Box 36, Folder 545)
  - Capote, Truman: The Trinity Times, New York; school paper with writings by and about Capote (in Series I), 1933-1934 (Box 36, Folder 546)
  - Cox, Palmer: drawings (7 on 2 sheets) for The Brownies Abroad; ink and pencil on bristol board mounted on illustration board (in Series I), circa 1899 (Box 36, Folder 547)
  - Cox, Palmer: drawings (2) for "The Brownies' Quilting Bee"; ink and pencil on bristol board (in Series I), 1910 (Box 36, Folder 548)
  - Cox, Palmer: drawings (3) for "Brownie Scroll Puzzles: Blindman's Buff and the Dance," manufactured by McLoughlin Bros., New York; ink and watercolor on paper (in Series I), circa 1891 (Box 36, Folder 549)
  - Cox, Palmer: drawings (2) for "Brownie Scroll Puzzles: Hauling the Yule Log and Christmas Dinner," manufactured by McLoughlin Bros., New York; ink and watercolor on paper (in Series I), circa 1891 (Box 36, Folder 550)
  - Cox, Palmer: drawings (15 on 5 sheets), of Brownies for miscellaneous and unidentified series; ink and pencil on bristol board mounted on paper (in Series I), undated (Box 36, Folder 551)
  - Cox, Palmer: drawings (7) for August Flower and German Syrup Almanac; ink and pencil on paper, mounted on paper (in Series I), circa 1890 (Box 36, Folder 552)
  - Cox, Palmer: drawings (4) for Wit and Wisdom Well Worth Reading; ink and pencil on paper mounted on paper (in Series I), circa 1890 (Box 36, Folder 553)
  - Darley, Felix Octavius Carr: drawings (3) of trial scene from The Pickwick Papers, by Charles Dickens; "Figures used in 'Foraging Party' Large India Ink drawing for the late Wm. T. Blodgett"; and harvest scene, captioned "For Bank note co."; pencil and white crayon on paper (in Series I), undated (Box 36, Folder 554)
  - Darley, Felix Octavius Carr: drawings (3) for unidentified projects; pencil and crayon on paper (in Series I), undated (Box 36, Folder 555)
  - Doepler, Carl Emil: proof of engraved frontispiece from unidentified family atlas; engraved by C. Wise (in Series I), circa 1850 (Box 36, Folder 556)
  - Eaton, Caroline Ketcham: manuscript book, "Illustrated Alphabet for Little Folks"; ink and watercolor on paper (in Series I), circa 1890 (Box 36, Folder 557)
  - Eichenberg, Fritz: drawing of boy with goat presenting bird to queen; ink on bristol board (in Series I), undated (Box 36, Folder 558)
  - Falls, C. B. (Charles Buckles): proof prints (3) for The A.B.C. Book: color and black-and-white woodcuts (in Series I), circa 1923 (Box 36, Folder 559)
  - Field, Eugene: manuscript, "Extinct Monsters," holograph poem with ink drawings (in Series I), 1895 Oct (Box 36, Folder 560)
  - Frost, A. B. (Arthur Burdett): drawings (2), "He Wasn't as Tired as He Looked"; and for Farming, by Richard Munkittrick; ink on paper and ink on bristol board (in Series I), 1890, circa 1892 (Box 36, Folder 561)
  - Gág, Wanda: drawings (2) for Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs; pencil, watercolor, and ink on paper (in Series I), undated (Box 36, Folder 562)
  - Gladstone, W. E. (William Ewart): essay, "Personal recollections of Arthur Henry Hallam"; holograph, bound with an extra-illustrated published version, "Arthur Henry Hallam," reprinted from the Youth's Companion, January 6, 1898 (in Series I), 1896, 1898 (Box 37, Folder 563)
  - Gruelle, Johnny: drawing for covers for Raggedy Andy Stories; watercolor, ink, and pencil on bristol board (in Series I), circa 1920 (Box 38, Folder 564)
  - Halm, George R.: drawings (2) for "Answered Riddle Jingles"; ink and pencil on bristol board, for St. Nicholas Magazine; ink and pencil on card (in Series I), undated (Box 38, Folder 565)
  - Herford, Oliver: drawing, "Scene II"; ink and pencil on bristol board (in Series I), undated (Box 38, Folder 566)
  - Hersey, Roscoe: workbook of designs and patterns; watercolor (in Series II), undated (Box 38, Folder 567)
  - Howard, C. J., drawing, "Hey Diddle Diddle," pencil on paper (in Series I), undated (Box 38, Folder 568)
  - Howard, Justin H.: drawing for The Doings of the Alphabet; watercolor and pencil on paper (in Series I), circa 1869 (Box 38, Folder 569)
  - Humphrey, Maud: drawing, "Dolly in Danger," for Little Brighteyes Story Book; watercolor on paper (in Series I), circa 1901 (Box 38, Folder 570)
  - Hurd, Clement: Proof print of dust jacket for Goodnight Moon (in Series I), undated (Box 38, Folder 571)
  - Ives, Sarah Noble: drawings (3) for The Night Before Christmas; watercolor, ink, and pencil on paper, mounted on illustration board (in Series I), circa 1907 (Box 38, Folder 572)
  - Johnston, David Claypoole: illustrations from Charcoal Sketches, or Night Scenes in the Metropolis, by J. G. Neal; folio sheet with four etchings (in Series I), 1838 (Box 38, Folder 573)
  - Kelly, Walt: drawings (11) for "Cinderella and the Three Bears"; ink and pencil on paper, with a set of hand-colored prints, ink and watercolor on photostat (in Series I), 1951 (Box 38, Folder 574-575)
  - Kemble, E. W. (Edward Windsor): drawings (2), "A Corner in Japan," for "The New Orleans Exposition," by Eugene V. Smalley, and "old blind Negro," ink and pencil on bristol board; tear sheet from Collier's with Kemble cartoon of William Andrews Clark titled "The Nation's Loss"; and halftone portrait of Kemble (in Series I), 1885, 1907, undated (Box 38, Folder 576)
  - Lawson, Robert: drawing for Ben and Me; ink and Chinese white on paper (in Series I), circa 1939 (Box 38, Folder 577)
  - McLoughlin Brothers, Inc.: drawings for cover of Little Stories for Little Folks and The Three Bears; hand-colored proofs (in Series I), 1890, 1892 (Box 38, Folder 578)
  - McLoughlin Brothers, Inc.: proof prints from pirated editions of Dean's Home Pantomime Toy Books (in Series I), circa 1880 (Box 38, Folder 579)
  - Merrill, Frank T.: drawing for "Captain January" series, by Laura E. Richards; ink, pencil, and Chinese white on paper (in Series I), 1893 (Box 38, Folder 580)
  - Miller, Bertha E. Mahony: certificate from Women's National Book Association (in Series I), 1955 (Box 38, Folder 581)
  - Mitchell, John Ames: drawing for "My Uncle Jehosaphat"; ink and pencil on illustration board (in Series I), circa 1876 (Box 38, Folder 582)
  - Newell, Peter: drawing, "Jimmieboy and the Gold Fish," for John Kendrick Bangs story; ink, wash, and Chinese white on illustration board (in Series I), 1895 (Box 38, Folder 583)
  - Opper, Frederick Burr: drawings (8) for "The Jolly Gymnasium"; watercolor, gouache, and pencil on paper (in Series I), undated (Box 39, Folder 584)
  - Petersham, Maude and Miska: An American ABC; proof sheets (11) for cover/dust jacket (in Series I), 1941 (Box 39, Folder 585)
  - Pyle, Howard: page proofs (8) of Sabbath Thoughts (in Series I), undated (Box 39, Folder 586)
  - Rhead, Louis: drawings (4 on 1 sheet) for Tom Brown's School Days, by Thomas Hughes; ink and pencil on paper, with printed initial attached for scale, circa 1910 (Box 39, Folder 587)
  - Richardson, Frederick: drawings (2) for Blue Fairy Book and Red Fairy Book, by Andrew Lang; ink and watercolor on paper (in Series I), circa 1930 (Box 39, Folder 588)
  - Rogers, W. A. (William Allen): drawings (19) for Toby Tyler, or, Ten Weeks with a Circus, by James Otis; ink and pencil on paper mounted on cardboard (in Series I), circa 1881 (Box 39, Folder 589-593)
  - Sewell, Helen: drawings (3) for Ten Saints, by Eleanor Farjeon; ink, pencil, and Chinese white on paper (in Series I), circa 1936 (Box 40, Folder 594)
  - Smith, E. Boyd (Elmer Boyd): drawing, "Trouble," for After They Came Out of The Ark; watercolor, ink, and pencil on paper (in Series I), circa 1918 (Box 40, Folder 595)
  - Tenggren, Gustaf: drawing, "My Old Kentucky Home," for Sing for America, by Opal Wheeler; watercolor and pencil on illustration board (in Series I), circa 1944 (Box 40, Folder 596)
  - Thackeray, William Makepeace: letter to unidentified boy, regarding his request for an autograph; with albumen photograph of Thackeray and reprint of letter issued as holiday greeting by collector Thomas F. Madigan (in Series I), 1852, 1928 (Box 40, Folder 597)
  - Van Loon, Hendrik Willem: drawings (8) for The Message of the Bells; watercolor and ink on paper (in Series I), 1942 (Box 40, Folder 598)
  - Walt Disney Productions: drawing, "The Faithful Little Men Watched Over Their Princess," for Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs; pencil on paper (in Series I), circa 1937 (Box 40, Folder 599)
  - Walt Disney Productions: drawing, "An Unhappy Happy," animation cell for Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs; paint on celluloid, framed (in Series I), circa 1937 (Box 41, Folder 600)
  - Walt Disney Productions: story board sheets (2) for Ben and Me, after Robert Lawson; crayon on paper mounted on paper (in Series I), 1953 (Box 40, Folder 601)
  - Wentworth, Jaazaniah: poem, "Education"; holograph (in Series II), 1821 Mar 15 (Box 40, Folder 602)
  - Winter, Milo: drawing, "Beffa settled down comfortably," for Nuova, or The New Bee, by Vernon Kellogg; ink on paper (in Series I), circa 1920 (Box 40, Folder 603)
  - Young, Art: drawing for "Seein' Things," by Eugene Field; ink on paper (in Series I), 1897 (Box 40, Folder 604)
  - Zemach, Margot: drawing for Jake and Honeybunch Go to Heaven; watercolor and pencil on illustration board (in Series I), circa 1982 (Box 40, Folder 605)
  - Unidentified artist: drawing ["Amsterdam St. Nicholas"], signed "HGH"; watercolor and ink on illustration board (in Series I), undated (Box 40, Folder 606)
  - Unidentified artist: drawing of two children playing with blocks, signed "W"; ink on bristol board (in Series I), undated (Box 40, Folder 607)
  - Unidentified artist: album, "Pictures from Life," created for Caroline Frothingham Neal; collages with narrative inscribed in ink (in Series II), 1865 (Box 40, Folder 608)
  - Anglund, Joan Walsh: drawings (12) for In a Pumpkin Shell; ink and pencil on paper (in Series I), circa 1960 (Box 42, Folder 609)
  - Anglund, Joan Walsh: drawings (8) for In a Pumpkin Shell; ink and pencil on paper (in Series I), circa 1960 (Box 42, Folder 610-611)
  - Attwood, Francis Gilbert: drawing, "Dance of the Fairies," for The Fairies' Festival, by John Witt Randall; ink and wash on illustration board (in Series I), circa 1894 (Box 42, Folder 612)
  - Bensel, Edmund Birckhead: drawing, "Meeting of the prince & enlarged fairy" for The Floating Prince, by Frank R. Stockton; pencil and ink wash on paper (in Series I), circa 1880 (Box 42, Folder 613)
  - Birch, Reginald Bathurst: drawing, "'I've got a great deal to thank your Lordship for,' said Higgins," for Little Lord Fauntleroy, by Frances Hodgson Burnett; ink, pencil, and Chinese white on paper (in Series I), 1886 (Box 42, Folder 614)
  - Birch, Reginald Bathurst: drawing, "Mr. Mordaunt held the small hand in his as he looked down at the child's face," for Little Lord Fauntleroy, by Frances Hodgson Burnett; watercolor on illustration board (in Series I), 1916 (Box 42, Folder 615)
  - Bruton, W.: drawings (20) for Johnny Headstrong's Trip to Coney Island; ink and pencil on bristol board, with publisher's storage portfolio (in Series I), circa 1882 (Box 42, Folder 616-618)
  - Cruikshank, George: drawing, "Bacchanalian Composition"; pencil and watercolor on paper (in Series I), undated (Box 43, Folder 619)
  - Darley, Felix Octavius Carr: drawings (5) for Great Expectations, The Old Curiosity Shop, and Oliver Twist, by Charles Dickens; pencil on paper, ink and wash on paper (in Series I), undated (Box 43, Folder 620)
  - Darley, Felix Octavius Carr: drawings (2) for Wing and Wing, by James Fenimore Cooper; sepia wash and pencil on bristol board (in Series I), circa 1842 (Box 43, Folder 621)
  - Daugherty, James: drawing, "Abraham Lincoln comforting the wounded at Gettysburg," for Abraham Lincoln; pencil and red pencil on paper (in Series I), undated (Box 43, Folder 622)
  - Denslow, W. W. (William Wallace): drawing, "Captain Bing was a Pirate King...," for Father Goose: His Book, by L. Frank Baum; ink, gouache, black chalk and pencil on paper, 1899 (Box 43, Folder 623)
  - Frost, A. B. (Arthur Burdett): drawings (2) for Uncle Remus, His Songs and Sayings, by Joel Chandler Harris; ink on paper (in Series I), circa 1895 (Box 43, Folder 624)
  - Gammon, Elizabeth: sampler; embroidery on linen (in Series II), circa 1795 (Box 43, Folder 625)
  - Graffam, Mary: sampler; embroidery on linen (in Series II), 1794 (Box 43, Folder 626)